# Oskar John Hollinsworth

Curriculum Vitae

6 Hamonde Close
Edgware
HA8 8TG

Ø 07833106245
☎ 02086215123

☑ oskar.hollinsworth@gmail.com
 ojh31.github.io

### About Me

I am currently studying undergraduate Mathematics at **Trinity College, Cambridge**. I intend to specialise in statistics in order to gain a deep understanding of the most applicable areas of mathematics. I also love using computer programming to solve problems efficiently.

I am much more well-rounded as a student than most of my peers in scientific subjects. I enjoy public speaking, especially debating, which I can engage in through the Cambridge Union. I have developed my social and interpersonal skills while looking after those in need of First Aid. I help to raise money for data-backed charities which involves a great deal of teamwork and planning. I tend to be able to communicate mathematical and scientific concepts better than most too, having worked as a maths tutor for many years. I also rely on this ability twice a week when I have to write out solutions to problem sheets and defend them in an interview with a Cambridge academic.

## Experience

#### Vocational

2011-2013 Private Maths Tutor.

Tutor in Mathematics to GCSE grade. £15/hour for home tuition

2013-2014 **School Maths Buddy**.

Official weekly tuition organised by the school in AS-level Core Mathematics for Year 12 students

2013 Financial Director, Young Enterprise.

On the board of directors of a clothing brand start-up as part of an international competition between schools

2014 AIG Science Team at the European Headquarters.

I shadowed the Quantitative Analysts, Quantitative Developers and Data Scientists who use statistics to optimise the selection process of the most profitable Broker Distribution Managers

2016 Centre for Pathogen Evolution, Zoology Department, Cambridge University.

I did original research in the linear regression of antigenic distance from amino acid substitution data

#### Miscellaneous

2008–2013 Learning Resources Centre Officer.

Allocated the booking of school computers and books

2011–2012 Student Officer.

School prefect assisting primarily at Open Evenings for parents

2013–2014 Learning Resources Centre Co-ordinator.

More senior managerial role leading a team of officers in managing school facilities

2015–2016 First Aider, St John's Ambulance.

I help to provide First Aid cover for various events in Cambridge

2016- **Digital Content Officer**, Giving What We Can, 80000 hours.

I manage eacambridge.org and edit videos from speaker events.

#### Qualifications

- 11 A\* grades and 1 A grade at GCSE
- 7 A grades at AS level
- o 3 A\* grades in Mathematics, Further Mathematics and Physics at A2 level
- S1S in STEP (Sixth Term Examination Papers)

- 2015 STEP I, S (Outstanding).
   Cambridge Entrance Paper
   2015 STEP II. 1 (Very Good).
- 2015 **STEP II**, 1 (Very Good). Cambridge Entrance Paper
- 2015 **STEP III**, S (Outstanding). Cambridge Entrance Paper
- 2015 **Mathematics**, A\*. A Level
- 2015 Further Mathematics, A\*. A Level

- 2015 **Physics**, A\*. A Level
- 2014 **Chemistry**, A. AS level
- 2014 **History**, A. AS level
- 2014 **Critical Thinking**, A. AS level
- 2013 **Religious Studies**, A. AS Level

## Extended Project

title What are the limits of mathematics?

description I wrote a dissertation discussing the philosophical implications of certain surprising results in Mathematical Logic. I also gave an accompanying presentation where I had to explain the central ideas to a general audience.

 $URL \quad https://drive.google.com/file/d/0Bwsr26lgIa\_6TWhGSXdhMHRiNk0/view?usp=sharing \\ grade \quad A$ 

#### Accolades

NB: My school gave out only **one prize** for each subject/category each year **out of 300 students** along with only a couple of awards.

Year 7 Outstanding Student of the Year, Special

Category Prize.

Mathematics, Subject Prize.

Progress in P.E., Award.

Progress in History, Award.

Contribution to School Community, Award.

Year 8 Science, Subject Prize.

History, Subject Prize.

Religious Studies, Subject Prize.

Progress in Drama, Award.

Progress in Technology, Award.

Contribution to School Community, Award.

Gold Junior Maths Challenge, Certificate.

World Maths Day, 91st in the world.

Problem Solving Journal, Solution cited.

Year 9 **Chemistry**, Chosen to perform practical demonstrations for prospective students and parents.

School Spokesperson, Awards Evening.

Team Maths Challenge, UKMT.

Mathematics, Subject Prize.

Progress in History, Award.

Progress in Spanish, Award.

Year 10 History, Subject Prize.

Spanish, Subject Prize.

Religious Studies, Subject Prize.

English Literature, Award.

Year 11 ESU London Debate Challenge, School Team.

**ESU Public Speaking Competition**, *Questioner* at regional schools heat.

**Excellent Academic Attainment on report**, *Gold Certificate*.

Year 12 Gold in Senior Maths Challenge, Best in Year.

Whole school Debating Competition,

Semi-finals.

MACE debating competition, London Finals.

Outstanding all round achievement at GCSE,

Award.

Student of the Month, Award.

Year 13 Gave practical demonstration of gyroscopes,

Science Week.

Runner up, ESU MACE London Final.

Mathematics, Award.

## Markup and Programming Languages

Python Basic proficiency
HTML Some experience
CSS Some experience

LATEX Basic proficiency
JavaScript Some experience
C++ Some experience